{"Topic": "Insurance and Finance", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "icwise Questions - Insurance and General Finance related Questions", "op1": "Insurance companies", "op2": "Banks", "op3": "NABARD", "op4": "RBI", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following types of companies/organisations issue ULIP?", "op1": "ICICI prudential", "op2": "ING Vysya", "op3": "National Securities Depository Limited", "op4": "New India Assurance company", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which amongst the following is not an insurance company functioning in India?", "op1": "General insurance company", "op2": "New India assurance company", "op3": "Oriental insurance company", "op4": "Life Insurance Corporation of India", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the only public sector company in the field of life insurance?", "op1": "Death coverage", "op2": "Life insurance", "op3": "Savings for future", "op4": "Provident fund", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "\"A contract that pledges payment of an agreed upon amount to the person (or his/her nominee) on the happening of an event covered against\" is technically known as", "op1": "New India Assurance Ltd.", "op2": "Insurance Australia Group", "op3": "Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc.", "op4": "Allianz", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "With which of the following did the State Bank of India enter into a joint venture agreement for undertaking general insurance business?", "op1": "RBI", "op2": "AMFI", "op3": "IRDA", "op4": "SEBI", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the regulator of insurance sector in India?", "op1": "Indemnity", "op2": "Coverage", "op3": "Misuse Alert", "op4": "Annuity"}, {"Question": "Which of the following terms is NOT related to the insurance sector?", "op1": "ECGC", "op2": "NABARD", "op3": "SIDBI", "op4": "IRDA", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following public sector companies/organizations provides insurance cover to exporters?", "op1": "Instalment", "op2": "Contribution", "op3": "Premium", "op4": "EMI", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The insurance companies collect a fixed amount from its customers at a fixed interval of time. What is it called?", "op1": "Only (a)", "op2": "Only (a) and (b)", "op3": "Only (b) and (c)", "op4": "All the three", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is/are the various types of insurance?", "op1": "Life Insurance Corporation", "op2": "Oriental Insurance Company", "op3": "New India Assurance", "op4": "General Insurance Company", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following insurance companies gives the slogan Prithvi, Agni, Jal, Akash - Sab ki Surakhsa Hamare Paas?Life Insurance CorporationOriental Insurance CompanyNew India AssuranceGeneral Insurance CompanyAnswer (b).  12.With which of the fields is actuarial science associated?InsuranceBankingMicro-financeSpace technologyAnswer (a).   13.Which of the following terms is used in the field of finance and banking?ElasticityInflationPulse rateHot wavesAnswer (b).  14.Expand the term IFRS.Indian Financial Reporting StandardsIndian Financial Reporting SystemsInternational Financial Reporting StandardsInternational Financial Reporting SystemsAnswer (c).  15.What does the term FSDC, used in financial sectors stand for?Financial Security and Development CouncilFinancial Stability and Development CouncilFiscal Security and Development ConventionFiscal Stability and Development CouncilAnswer (b).  16.Under the ESOP, who of the following are offered shares in the company?EmployeesExisting ShareholdersPromotersNRIsAnswer (a).  17.On which one of the following issues can SEBI penalize any company in India?Violation of Banking Regulation ActViolation of foreign portfolio investment guidelinesFor violation of Negotiable Instrument ActOnly 1Only 2Only 3All the threeAnswer (b).  ", "op1": "Insurance", "op2": "Banking", "op3": "Micro-finance", "op4": "Space technology"}, {"Question": "With which of the fields is actuarial science associated?", "op1": "Elasticity", "op2": "Inflation", "op3": "Pulse rate", "op4": "Hot waves", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following terms is used in the field of finance and banking?", "op1": "Indian Financial Reporting Standards", "op2": "Indian Financial Reporting Systems", "op3": "International Financial Reporting Standards", "op4": "International Financial Reporting Systems"}, {"Question": "Expand the term IFRS.", "op1": "Financial Security and Development Council", "op2": "Financial Stability and Development Council", "op3": "Fiscal Security and Development Convention", "op4": "Fiscal Stability and Development Council", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "What does the term FSDC, used in financial sectors stand for?", "op1": "Employees", "op2": "Existing Shareholders", "op3": "Promoters", "op4": "NRIs", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Under the ESOP, who of the following are offered shares in the company?", "op1": "Only 1", "op2": "Only 2", "op3": "Only 3", "op4": "All the three", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Expand the term CCEA as used in administrative circles", "op1": "Cabinet Committee on External Affairs", "op2": "Cabinet Committee on Economic Affairs", "op3": "Cabinet Council on External Affairs", "op4": "Cabinet Council on Economic Affairs", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": " Foreign exchange reserves of India are kept in the custody of which of the following?", "op1": "Reserve bank of India", "op2": "All public sector banks", "op3": "Foreign banks in India", "op4": "Government treasury", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Fiscal policy is concerned with which of the following?", "op1": "Export and import", "op2": "Public revenue and expenditure", "op3": "Issue of currency", "op4": "Population control", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": " Which of the following is NOT a part of India\u2019s money market?", "op1": "Bill market", "op2": "Call money market", "op3": "Banks", "op4": "Indian Gold council", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the regulator of the credit rating agencies in India?", "op1": "RBI", "op2": "SBI", "op3": "SEBI", "op4": "ICRA", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "  FDI refers to", "op1": "Fixed Deposits in India", "op2": "Foreign Direct Investment", "op3": "Foreign Deposits in India", "op4": "Future Derivative Investment", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "State financial Corporations give assistance mainly to develop which of the following?", "op1": "Small and medium scale industries", "op2": "Agricultural sector", "op3": "Cotton industry", "op4": "Large scale industries", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Yogakshemam Vahamyaham is the tag line of \u2013", "op1": "HDFC Life Insurance", "op2": "SBI Life Insurance", "op3": "Bharti AXA Life Insurance", "op4": "Life Insurance Corporation", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Bonds issued by Indian entities outside India but denominated in Indian rupees are known as \u2013", "op1": "Desi Bonds", "op2": "NRI Bonds", "op3": "Pravasi Bonds", "op4": "Masala Bonds", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Aviva plc is an multinational insurance company headquartered in \u2013", "op1": "Munich", "op2": "Paris", "op3": "London", "op4": "Tokyo", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Sar Utha ke Jiyo is the tag line of \u2013", "op1": "HDFC Life Insurance", "op2": "Birla Sun Life Insurance", "op3": "Aviva Life Insurance", "op4": "Sahara India Life Insurance", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "AXA is an insurance company headquartered in \u2013", "op1": "London", "op2": "Tokyo", "op3": "New York", "op4": "Paris"}]}